Guide to the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Manuscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- File List, Series I
  - "B"
    - Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824
      - AMS of The Corsair (Canto III, stanza xvii, lines 1690f.), n.d.
        Tinker 483
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 638
      - AMS of The Corsair (Canto I, stanza xi, lines 277-80), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 169)
        Tinker 484
      - AMS of Don Juan (Canto I, stanzas clxvi-clxvii), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 170)
        Tinker 485
      - AMS of Don Juan (Canto IX), 1822
        Tinker 486
        See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 639
      - AMS of "Hints from Horace" (lines 657-58 with the accompanying lengthy note), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 171)
        Tinker 487
        See also: Oversize, Box 17, folder 640
      - AMS of "Then peace to thy spirit, my earliest Friend" (Box 5, Folder 172)
        Tinker 488
      - ALS to William John Bankes, Cheltenham, 1812 Sep 28 (Box 5, Folder 173)
        Tinker 489
      - ALS to Samuel Taylor Coleridge, London, 1815 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 174)
        Tinker 490
      - ALS to Robert Charles Dallas, [Newstead Abbey], 1811 Oct 10 (Box 5, Folder 175)
        Tinker 491
      - ALS to Henry Joseph Drury, Falmouth, 1809 Jun 25 (Box 5, Folder 176)
        Tinker 493
      - ALS to John Fitzgibbon, Earl of Clare, Cambridge, 1807 Aug 20 (Box 5, Folder 177)
        Tinker 494
      - ALS to [John Hanson?], Newstead Abbey, 1809 Jan 10 (Box 5, Folder 178)
        Tinker 495
      - ALS to Leigh Hunt, [London], 1815 Jul 28 (Box 5, Folder 179)
        Tinker 496
      - ALS to the Hon. Douglas James William Kinnaird, Ravenna, 1820 Sep 17 (Box 6, Folder 180)
        Tinker 497
      - ALS to Edward Noel Long, Cambridge, 1807 Jun 29 (Box 6, Folder 181)
        Tinker 498
      - ANS to John Murray, [London], 1813 Dec 7 (Box 6, Folder 182)
        Tinker 499
      - ALS to James Perry, London, 1814 Oct 5 (Box 6, Folder 183)
        Tinker 500
      - ALS to Alexander Rae, [London], 1815 Nov 19 (Box 6, Folder 184)
        Tinker 501
      - ALS to John Ridge, Cambridge, 1807 Dec 14 (Box 6, Folder 185)
        Tinker 502
      - ALS to James Wedderburn Webster, [London], 1816 Apr 16 (Box 6, Folder 186)
        Tinker 504
      - ALS to Lady --?, [London], [ca. 1814?] (Box 6, Folder 187)
        Tinker 505
    - Byron, Richard Byron, Baron, 1605-1679
      - ALS to Rupert, Prince of Bohemia, Newark, 1644 Apr 13 (Box 6, Folder 188)
        Tinker 598
  - "C"
    - Caine, Hall, Sir, 1853-1931
      - TLS to C. Fred Kenyon, Isle of Man, 1901 Jul 4 (Box 6, Folder 189)
      - TLS to C. Fred Kenyon, Isle of Man, 1904 Nov 7 (Box 6, Folder 190)
        Tinker 600
      - Notice from Postmaster, addressed to Hall Caine, Manchester, 1901 Sep 24 (Box 6, Folder 191)
        With holograph note from Caine on back, signed Tinker 601
      - Reproduction of photograph of Caine, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Callcott, Maria, Lady, 1785-1842
      - ALS (last page) to Mrs. Utterson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Calverley, Charles Stuart, 1831-1884
      - ALS to Mr. Chambers, Ascot, n.y. Sep 29 (Box 6, Folder 194)
        Tinker 603
    - Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881
      - ANS with endorsement, 1854 Feb 14 (Box 6, Folder 195)
        Tinker 608
      - ALS to Frederic Chapman or John Chapman, Chelsea, 1851 Oct 14 (Box 6, Folder 196)
        Tinker 609
      - ALS to John Ruskin, Chelsea, 1866 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 197)
        Tinker 610
    - Carnarvon, Henry Howard Molyneux, Earl of, 1831-1890
      - 2 ALS to [Edward Craven?] Hawtrey, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 198)
        Accompanied by engraving of Carnarvon
    - Carpenter, Mary, 1807-1877
      - ALS to Miss Smith, Bristol, 1853 Mar 10 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Carpenter, William, 1797-1874
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, n.y. May 18 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Carter, Elizabeth, 1717-1806
      - Prayer, autograph manuscript, 1763 (Box 6, Folder 201)
        Tinker 616
    - Cassell, John, 1817-1865
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1858 May 19 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
      - ALS to Mrs. Anna Maria Hall, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 203)
        Accompanied by an engraving of Chambers
    - Chamier, Frederick, 1796-1870
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Brighton, 1843 Nov 23 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Chatterton, Georgiana, Lady, 1806-1876
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1865, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Chesterton, George Laval
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1858, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Christie, Richard Copley, 1830-1901
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, 1898 Jul 23 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Clare, John, 1793-1864
      - AL, signed Percey Green, to Messrs. Taylor and Hessey, 1822 Oct 19 (Box 6, Folder 208)
        Sending a poem, "Ballad." Accompanied by a printed copy of the letter clipped from the Times Literary Supplement, 1930 Jul 10. Tinker 634
    - Clarke, Thomas
      - 4 ALS to William Johnston Temple, 1767-87 (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Clinton, Henry Fynes, 1781-1852
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Welwyn Herts, 1850 Jan 22 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Clough, Arthur Hugh, 1819-1861
      - ALS to Thomas Burbidge, London, [1859?] Aug 15 (Box 6, Folder 211)
        Tinker 640
    - Cobbold, Richard, 1797-1877
      - ALS to the Reverend S. Parkens, Wortham, 1855 Mar 1 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834
      - AMS of prospectus for "Six Lectures on Revealed Religion, its' Corruptions and Political Views. by S.T. Coleridge", [1795] (Box 6, Folder 213)
        Tinker 656
      - AMS fragment; notes of a mathematical and philosophical nature, 1800 Nov 9 (Box 6, Folder 214)
        Tinker 657
      - AMS of "The Dark Ladié, a Fragment", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 215)
        Tinker 658
      - AMS, "Where is the grave of Sir Arthur O'Rellian?", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 216)
        Tinker 659
      - AMS of "My baptismal birth day", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 217)
        Tinker 660
      - AMS of "On my spiritual Birth-day, October 28 - Lines composed on a Sick bed under severe bodily Suffering, by S.T. Coleridge", 1833 Aug 6 (Box 6, Folder 218)
        Tinker 661
      - AMS of "Notes on Mr H's Letter", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 219)
        Tinker 662
      - ALS to Mrs. Charles Aders, London, 1826 Mar 8 (Box 6, Folder 220)
        Tinker 663
      - ALS to William Lisle Bowles, [Stowey], [1797 Mar 16] (Box 6, Folder 221)
        Tinker 664
      - ALS to Joseph Cottle, [Alfoxden], [1798 Mar 13] (Box 6, Folder 222)
        Tinker 665
      - ALS to R. Fieldier (?), Highgate, 1831 Nov 10 (Box 7, Folder 223)
        Tinker 666
      - ALS to Charles Mathews, n.p., [1819] (Box 7, Folder 224)
        Tinker 669
      - Prospectus of The Friend, a weekly essay, by S.T. Coleridge, 1808 (Box 7, Folder 225)
        First edition. On p. [3] ANS from Robert Southey to Grosvenor Charles Bedford, Kendal, [1808] Nov 4 Tinker 688, Tinker 1939
    - Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889
      - ALS to B.E. Joseph, London, 1887 Mar 21 (Box 7, Folder 226)
        Tinker 717
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, London, 1878 Mar 13 (Box 7, Folder 227)
        Tinker 720
    - Colton, C. C. (Charles Caleb), 1780?-1832
      - Verses addressed "to Sands", 1819 May 12 (Box 7, Folder 228)
        Pencil note on verso, attributing authorship to Colton
    - Constable, Archibald, 1774-1827
      - ALS to William Fraser, Edinburgh, 1827 Feb 3 (Box 7, Folder 229)
        Tinker 738
    - Constable, John, 1776-1837
      - ALS to Robert Balmanno, [London], 1829 Apr 29 (Box 7, Folder 230)
        Tinker 739
      - ALS to John Britton, n.p., 1834 Feb 2 (Box 7, Folder 231)
        Tinker 740
    - Convers, D.
      - 2 ALS to Mrs. R. W. Woodward, Oxford, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 232)
        Dated 1898 Dec 14 and 1898 Dec 24. With envelopes. Letter dated 1898 Dec 24 encloses ALS from Clara Pater to D. Convers, [1898] Dec 17, with photogravure of Walter Pater. Tinker 1644
        See also: Box 11, folder 473
    - Cook, Eliza, 1818-1889
      - ALS to James Fleming, Brighton, [18]64 Oct 6 (Box 7, Folder 233)
        With envelope addressed to Fleming postmarked [18]61 Oct 6
      - ALS to [Mr. Morton?], 9 Gloucester Buildings, Old Kent Road, [18]41 Dec 19 (Box 7, Folder 234)
        Accompanied by engraving of Cook
    - Cook, John Douglas, 1808?-1868
      - Autograph note to an unidentified recipient, London, [18]65 Nov 7 (Box 7, Folder 235)
        Signed "Ed. of S. Review."
    - Corser, Thomas, 1793-1876
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Manchester, 1862 Apr 11 (Box 7, Folder 236)
        Tinker 743
    - Cotman, John Sell, 1762-1842
      - ANS to Josiah French, [London], 1834 Jan 17 (Box 7, Folder 237)
        Tinker 744
    - Cottle, Joseph, 1770-1853
      - ANS to an unidentified recipient, Bristol, 1797 Mar 27 (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - Cowper, William, 1731-1800
      - ALS to Harriet (Cowper), Lady Hesketh, Olney, 1787 Nov 10 (Box 7, Folder 239)
        Tinker 747
      - ALS to Harriet (Cowper), Lady Hesketh, Weston Lodge, Olney, 1788 May 1 (Box 7, Folder 240)
        Tinker 748
      - ALS to Joseph Johnson, Olney, 1781 Aug 6 (Box 7, Folder 241)
        Tinker 749
      - ALS to Joseph Johnson, [Olney], 1782 Feb 17 (Box 7, Folder 242)
        Tinker 750
      - ALS to John Newton, Olney, 1780 Jul 4 (Box 7, Folder 243)
        Tinker 751
      - ALS to Samuel Rose, Olney, 1789 Oct 4 (Box 7, Folder 244)
        Tinker 752
      - ALS to Samuel Rose, [Olney], 1793 Jun 18 (Box 7, Folder 245)
        Includes "A Sonnet Addressed to Mr. Phillips now in confinement at Leicester." Enclosure: ALS to William Cowper from Richard Phillips asking for a sonnet to help the latter's cause. 1793 Jun 12 Tinker 753
      - ALS to William Cawthorne Unwin, [Olney], 1780 Aug 6 (Box 7, Folder 246)
        Tinker 754
    - Cox, George W. (George William), 1827-1902
      - Autograph note, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 247)
        Concerning p. 262 of Edward Bradley's Glencreggan (London, 1861). With explanatory note by Bradley.
    - Crabbe, George, 1754-1832
      - AMS of "Lay on the Piano Forte", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 248)
        Tinker 760
      - ALS to [Hans Busk], London, [1819] May 18 (Box 7, Folder 249)
        Tinker 764
      - ALS to Elizabeth Charter, Trowbridge, 1819 Mar 26 (Box 7, Folder 250)
        Tinker 766
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., London, [1822 Jun] (Box 7, Folder 251)
        Tinker 767
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, [1823?] May 19 (Box 7, Folder 252)
        Tinker 768
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1824 Dec 2 (Box 7, Folder 253)
        Tinker 769
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Hampstead, 1826 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 254)
        Accompanied by portrait of George Crabbe Tinker 770
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1827 May 17 (Box 7, Folder 255)
        Tinker 771
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1827 Jun 30 (Box 7, Folder 256)
        Tinker 772
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1828 Jan 18-20 (Box 7, Folder 257)
        Tinker 773
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1829 Apr 9 (Box 7, Folder 258)
        Tinker 774
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1829 Oct 19 (Box 7, Folder 259)
        Tinker 775
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1829 Nov 15 (Box 7, Folder 260)
        Tinker 776
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Trowbridge, 1830 Jun 10 (Box 7, Folder 261)
        Tinker 777
      - ALS to George Crabbe, Jr., Clifton, [1831?] Oct 28 (Box 7, Folder 262)
        Tinker 778
      - 3 ALS to Mrs. Hope, [London], [1819] Jun 3-19 (Box 7, Folder 263)
        Tinker 780, Tinker 781, Tinker 782
    - Crabbe, George, 1785-1857
      - Certificate of honor from Bristol College, 1834 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa Richards, 1867-1906
      See: John Oliver Hobbes, Box 8,
      - folder 372
    - Croker, Thomas Crofton, 1798-1854
      - ALS to Mr. Fraser, Admiralty, London, 1829 Oct 8 (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Crome, John, 1769-1821
      - AMS of a bill to Miss Wilkin, for painting supplies and instruction, 1806 Dec (Box 7, Folder 266)
        Accompanied by autograph receipt signed and dated 1806 Dec 27 Tinker 801
    - Crowe, Eyre Evans, 1799-1868
      - ALS to [William Hepworth Dixon?], London, [1848?] Oct 29 (Box 7, Folder 267)
        Tinker 802
    - Crowe, J. A. (Joseph Archer), 1825-1896
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Leipzig, 1867 Nov 20 (Box 7, Folder 268)
    - Cumberland, George, 1754-1848
      - ANS to R. Phillips, Bristol, [1818 Dec] (Box 7, Folder 269)
        Signed with initials. On verso is note: "This paper was afterwards printed in the Sun newspaper." With ALS from R. Phillips to George Cumberland, 1818 Dec 7. Last page bears cancelled draft of Cumberland's reply. Tinker 803
    - Cunnigham, Allan, 1784-1842
      - ALS to Robert Cole, London, 1840 Dec 15 (Box 7, Folder 270)
        Accompanied by picture of Cunningham
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1828 May 27 (Box 7, Folder 271)
        Tinker 804
  - "D"
    - Dallas, Alexander R. C. (Alexander Robert Charles), 1791-1869
      - ALS to Robert Baldwin, Winchester, 1831 May 25 (Box 7, Folder 272)
        Removed from: Lord Byron's The Curse of Minerva (London, 1812) Tinker 589
    - Dallas, E. S. (Eneas Sweetland), 1828-1879
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, [18]63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 273)
    - Daniel, William Barker, 1753?-1833
      - Closing lines of ALS to [Robert Scott?], 1801 Aug 20 (Box 7, Folder 274)
    - Darley, George
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Clarence Club, London, 1838 Aug 13 (Box 7, Folder 275)
    - Davidson, Samuel, 1806-1898
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1868 Apr 9 (Box 7, Folder 276)
    - Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867
      - ALS to William S. Cardell, Yale College, 1821 Feb 16 (Box 7, Folder 277)
        Tinker 807
    - De La Mare, Walter John, 1873-1956
      - TLS to Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Anerley, 1922 Jan 2 (Box 7, Folder 278)
        Tinker 809
      - TLS to Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Anerley, 1922 Apr 3 (Box 7, Folder 279)
        Tinker 810
    - Delane, John Thadeus, 1817-1879
      - ALS to Mrs. Denman, London, n.y. Jun 26 (Box 7, Folder 280)
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, [1869] Jan 28 (Box 7, Folder 281)
        Tinker 816
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, n.y. Jun 30 (Box 7, Folder 282)
      - ALS to Arthur Helps, Trentham, Staffordshire, 1869 Jan 1 (Box 7, Folder 283)
    - Dibdin, Thomas Frognall, 1776-1847
      - ALS to [Rudolph] Ackermann, [London?], [1830] Mar 5 (Box 7, Folder 284)
        Tinker 818
      - ALS to James Fergusson, London, 1846 Jun 27 (Box 7, Folder 285)
      - ALS to [Alfred Robert] Freebairn, London, n.y. Jan 18 (Box 7, Folder 286)
      - ALS to Mrs. Goldsmid, [London?], 1844 Oct 16 (Box 7, Folder 287)
      - ALS to Joseph Hogarth, London, 1846 Jul 3 (Box 7, Folder 288)
    - Disraeli, Isaac, 1766-1848
      - ALS to Mr. Brandon, London (Box 7, Folder 289)
        Accompanied by slip of paper bearing the following holograph note, signed: "Beausobre Histoire critique du Manichei[sme] 2v. 4o. Am" and portrait of Disraeli. Tinker 832
    - Dixon, William Hepworth, 1821-1879
      - ALS to Miss Cobbe, London, 1888 Jan 23 (Box 7, Folder 290)
        Accompanied by Dixon's calling card
      - ALS to the Marquis of Lansdowne, n.y. Aug 2 (Box 7, Folder 291)
      - Correspondence with the editor of the Tomahawk, London, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 292)
        3 ALS to Dixon (1 from Arthur William à Beckett) and 1 ALS from him
    - Dobell, Sydney, 1824-1874
      - LS (last sheet) to [William Hepworth Dixon], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 293)
        In unidentified hand
    - Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921
      - AMS of two essays, "Dr. Johnson in Fleet Street", and "The First Editor of The Tatler, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 294)
        Tinker 833
      - ALS to Reginald John Smith, Ealing, 1904 Dec 5 (Box 7, Folder 295)
        Tinker 836
      - ALS to Reginald John Smith, Ealing, 1908 Oct 26 (Box 7, Folder 296)
        Includes AMS poem "A New Year's Rondeau" on p. 3 Tinker 837
    - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898
      - ALS to Colonel Todd, Oxford, 1876 Jul 21 (Box 7, Folder 297)
        Tinker 840
    - Dorset, Catherine Ann Turner, 1750?-1817?
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 298)
    - Drummond, Henry, Fl. 1843
      - ALS to Lady Strange, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 299)
        Paper watermarked 1843. A letter on heraldry with pen drawings to illustrate.
    - Duff-Gordon, Lucie, Lady, 1821-1869
      - ALS to Dr. Hawtrey, London, 1857 Apr 4 (Box 7, Folder 300)
        The date is in a different hand.
  - "E"
    - Eastlake, Elizabeth Rigby, Lady, 1809-1893
      - ALS to Miss Goldsmid, London, 1853 Dec 19 (Box 7, Folder 301)
    - Eden, Lady Lily
      - 3 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 302)
    - Edwards, Amelia Ann Blanford, 1831-1892
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1865, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 303)
    - Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926
      - TLS to Henry Clinton Hutchins, Cambridge, Mass., 1916 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 304)
    - Ellesmere, Francis Egerton, Earl of, 1800-1857
      - ALS to Mrs. (Anna) Jameson, Worsley, Manchester, 1843 Jan 9 (Box 7, Folder 305)
        Tinker 1025
      - ALS to Messrs. Smith, Worsley, Manchester, 1848 Dec 22 (Box 7, Folder 306)
        Accompanied by engraved portrait of Ellesmere
    - Elliot, Minto (Mrs.)
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Bristol, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 307)
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 308)
    - Elliott, Ebenezer, 1781-1849
      - Signature, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 309)
    - Eon de Beaumont, Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d', 1728-1810
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1763 Nov 10
        Probably to François-Joachim de Pierre de Bernis. Accompanied by two engraved portraits of the chevalier d'Eon as a man and as a woman. Tinker 1026
        See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 641
  - "F"
    - Ferguson, Samuel, Sir, 1810-1886
      - AL in the third person to the business manager of the Athenaeum, Dublin, 1867 May 18 (Box 8, Folder 310)
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Dublin, 1860 May 21 (Box 8, Folder 311)
    - Fergusson, James, 1808-1886
      - ALS to Joseph Hogarth, London, 1846 Jun 23 (Box 8, Folder 312)
        Accompanied by manuscript agreement between Fergusson and Hogarth, London, 1846 Jun 30
    - Field, Michael
      - 3 ALS to Elkin Mathews, 1894, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 313)
        Envelope with letter dated 1894 Aug 7
    - Flaxman, John, 1755-1826
      - ALS to William Hayley, n.p., [1797?] (Box 8, Folder 314)
        Tinker 1043
      - ALS to William Hayley, London, 1803 May 28 (Box 8, Folder 315)
        Tinker 1044
    - Fitzgerald, Percy Hetherington, 1834-1925
      - 4 ALS to unidentified recipients, London, 1898, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 316)
        Philological note, holograph, enclosed in one of the undated letters
    - Fitzpatrick, William John, 1830-1895
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Kilmand Manor, Stillorgan, Dublin, 1859 (Box 8, Folder 317)
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Kilmand Manor, Stillorgan, Dublin, n.y. Aug 26 (Box 8, Folder 318)
    - Ford, Richard, 1796-1858
      - 2 ALS to unidentified recipients, [18]56, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 319)
    - Forshaw, Charles F. (Charles Frederick), b. 1863
      - ALS to E. J. Collings, Bradford, 1898 Aug 21 (Box 8, Folder 320)
    - Forster, John, 1812-1876
      - ALS to [George William?] Manby, Broadstairs, Kent, 1851 Sep 10 (Box 8, Folder 321)
      - ALS to E. H. [Mayer?], London, n.y. Feb 24 (Box 8, Folder 322)
    - Freeman, Edward Augustus, 1823-1892
      - ALS to [Mandell?] Creighton, Wells, 1875 Feb 28 (Box 8, Folder 323)
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1818-1894
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, n.y. Nov 16 (Box 8, Folder 324)
        Accompanied by pen and ink sketch of Froude
    - Fry, Oliver Armstrong, 1855-
      - TLS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1901 Jan 8 (Box 8, Folder 325)
    - Fuseli, Henry, 1741-1825
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Somerset House, London, 1819 Feb 6 (Box 8, Folder 326)
        Tinker 1051
  - "G"
    - Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788
      - ALS to Mary (Gainsborough) Gibbon, [London?], [n.y. Apr 13] (Box 8, Folder 327)
        Tinker 1052
    - [Gale, Norman, 1862-1942]
      - AL to Mr. Morden, Oakfield Cottage, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 328)
    - Gales, Sarah
      - ALS in the third person to Mrs. Jobson Smith, The Mount, 1852 Mar 19 (Box 8, Folder 329)
        Accompanied by engraved portrait of Gales
    - Galt, John, 1779-1839
      - ALS to William Fraser, London, 1830 Jan 20 (Box 8, Folder 330)
        Accompanied by portrait of Galt
    - Garnett, Richard, 1835-1906
      - 2 ALS to Mr. Simpson, London, 1871, 1872 (Box 8, Folder 331)
    - Gillette, William, 1853-1937
      - TLS to Daniel Frohman, Hadlyme, Conn., 1926 May 28 (Box 8, Folder 332)
        Removed from: Arthur Conan Doyle and William Gillette's Sherlock Holmes: A Drama in Four Acts (London, 1922).
    - Gleig, G. R. (George Robert), 1796-1888
      - ALS to Miss Cutts, Ardchullarie, Callander, 1851 Jul 18 (Box 8, Folder 333)
      - ALS to Robert Walpole, War Office, London, 1845 Jul 25 (Box 8, Folder 334)
    - Godwin, William, 1756-1836
      - Signature, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 335)
        Accompanied by portrait of Godwin.
      - ALS to Joseph Parkes, London, 1829 Oct 1 (Box 8, Folder 336)
        Tinker 1080
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1885 Feb 24 (Box 8, Folder 337)
    - Grahame, Kenneth, 1859-1932
      - ALS to R. U. Johnson, England, 1912 Feb 1 (Box 8, Folder 338)
    - Grant, James, 1822-1887
      - ALS to James Robinson Planché, Sunningdale, Berks., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 339)
    - Gray, Thomas, 1716-1771
      - AMS of "Ode I. On the spring", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 340)
        18 words from stanza 2 Tinker 1163
    - Greg, William R. (William Rathbone), 1809-1881
      - ALS to Mrs. (Anna) Jameson, Windermere, [1854?] Jan 18 (Box 8, Folder 341)
        Tinker 1171
    - Griffith, Reginald Harvey, 1873-
      - ALS to Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Department of English, The University of Texas, Austin 12, 1944 Jun 21 (Box 8, Folder 342)
        Accompanied by a page from The Austin Statesman, 1944 Jun 8, containing a photograph of Griffith and an article concerning his retirement from the University of Texas.
    - Grosart, Alexander Balloch, 1827-1899
      - ALS to Thomas Hancock, Dublin, 1894 Oct 17 (Box 8, Folder 343)
    - Grote, George, 1794-1871
      - Page 3 of autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 344)
        Clipping of biographical interest pasted to bottom of page. Accompanied by engraved portrait of Grote.
    - Gurney, Anna, 1795-1857
      - Autograph manuscript, 1823 Sep 26 (Box 8, Folder 345)
        With caption, "Humble advice to R. F. & P. B."
    - Gurney, Hudson, 1775-1864
      - ALS to [Elizabeth] Fry, Warwick, 1831 Nov 29 (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - "H"
    - Hall, S. C. (Samuel Carter), 1800-1889
      - ALS to Mrs. S. C. Hall, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 347)
        Tinker 1180
      - Autograph copy of verses, signed, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 348)
        Accompanied by engraved portrait of S. C. Hall.
    - Hall, S. C., Mrs., 1800-1881
      - ALS to Mrs. Macquoid, Bannow Lodge, Boltons, West Brompton, S.W., n.y. Dec 23 (Box 8, Folder 349)
    - Halliday, Andrew, 1830-1877
      - ALS to George Loveday, London, 1873 Sep 3 (Box 8, Folder 350)
    - Halliwell-Phillips, J. O. (James Orchard), 1820-1889
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 17 Marine Terrace, Aberystwith, 1863 Aug 25 (Box 8, Folder 351)